<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>PowerShell - Category - JordanTheITGuy</title><link>http://jordantheitguy.com/categories/powershell/</link><description>PowerShell - Category - JordanTheITGuy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://jordantheitguy.com/categories/powershell/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mr Shiba What Time Is It - Get Time Remotely</title><link>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/mr-shiba-what-time-is-it-get-time-remotely/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/mr-shiba-what-time-is-it-get-time-remotely/</guid><description>If you’ve ever worked in a large distributed environment you’ve likely experienced time issues. Maybe it’s not even so much an issue as you just want to know where the heck in the world a machine is. Especially in the current state of the world where almost every other day I wake up and go “WHAT YEAR IS IT” every day is Monday and everything is always on fire
I’m sure you’re thinking can’t I just invoke command to it?</description></item><item><title>Finding OU's With Workstations - PowerShell Performance Is Weird</title><link>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/finding-ous-with-workstations-powershell-performance-is-weird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 12:17:06 -0400</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/finding-ous-with-workstations-powershell-performance-is-weird/</guid><description>I was recently asked to implement LAPS for a customer. Nothing unusual there. This particular environment was new to me which meant it was time to investigate their OU structure.
Why does OU structure matter? When implementing laps there are a few things to keep in mind. First, you need to extend the schema. Then you need to grant computers permission to access the newly created attributes… Well to accomplish this you need to assign the self permission in your root computers OU but are you sure you got them all?</description></item><item><title>PowerShell Copy to Clipboard</title><link>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell-copy-to-clipboard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 12:29:17 -0400</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell-copy-to-clipboard/</guid><description>Sometimes copy paste is just really hard. If you’ve ever found yourself working through multiple RDP sessions you’ve probably attempted to copy or paste something in a PowerShell session only to have it fail horribly. Maybe you’ve been trying to look at some returned data only to have it output in some weird list.
CLIP Struggling to copy the results of a PowerShell command to your clipboard so you can make a note?</description></item><item><title>PowerShell Get Members Of Group</title><link>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell_get_members_of_group/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell_get_members_of_group/</guid><description>Every now and again there comes a need to get the members of a group and manipulate that data in some fashion.
Now there are many ways to skin this cat and work with this data from VBscript, to utilizing DSquery to Quest Powershell CMDLETS to just raw powershell cmdlets.
Rather than spend time writing a new script every time you work at a different place or having to change constants in a script I spent some time writing a quick powershell script that accepts some variable information an outputs a CSV, or TXT file (your choice) with the user’s SAMaccountName combined with first and last name for all members of that group.</description></item><item><title>Powershell Change The Local Administrator Account/Password</title><link>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell_change_localadminpassword/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell_change_localadminpassword/</guid><description>What Happened? Back in May of 2014 Microsoft released a windows update – MS14-025 – that removed the ability to push out passwords to workstations remotely using group policy due to issues with elevation of privilege. If that patch is applied it’s a rather large pain to change the local admin after that without something like SCCM in place.
Working Around the Issue After working through some similar issues and reading a few TechNet Articles I decided to build a quick and slightly dirty powershell script to do several things as needed.</description></item></channel></rss>