<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>JordanTheITGuy</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/</link><description>Hiya, I'm JordanTheITGuy, I hope I wrote something at some point that you found useful.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Find Log4J With Intune Proactive Remediations</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/find-log4j-with-intune-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/find-log4j-with-intune-proactive-remediations/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/blogPosts/MakeScriptPackage.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>On December 10th 2021 CVE-2021-44228 was unveiled- queue the mass panic. A simple logging component which had been around for… forever in a whole bunch of things including but not limited to Minecraft.
Update: February 6th 2022 - It&rsquo;s worth nothing that even now three months later this vulnerability is still having massive impact all over the world as the threat hunting methods originally devised were limited in their nature. In fact, we have even seen cases where grey hat hackers were using the exploit to patch the exploit.]]></description></item><item><title>Automatic Deployment Rule Update ID Translation</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/automatic-deployment-rule-update-id-translation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/automatic-deployment-rule-update-id-translation/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/blogPosts/ADR-UpdateIDTranslation/UpdateGatherData.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>If you’ve ever worked with Automatic Deployment Rules, at some point an update has failed to download. While you might be familiar with the RuleEngine.log file, did know the “updateID” is the “CI_ID”? If you’ve ever tried to find a software update via CI_ID, you know you’re going to one of two places, and neither of them is the console. Essentially, if you’re here you’re looking for an easy way to figure out what update caused this error:</description></item><item><title>Query Defender for Endpoint Part 2</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/query-defender-for-endpoint-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/query-defender-for-endpoint-part-2/</guid><description>Part Two on Getting Data from Defender for Endpoint This blog is the second post in a multipart series on how to get data from Defender for endpoint and analyze the patching data that is returned. Previously, we covered how to build a token, and request data from the Defender for endpoint API. This time we will cover how to create an azure app registration that allows the minimum required permissions to gather this data.</description></item><item><title>Query Defender for Endpoint Part 1</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/query-defender-for-endpoint-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/query-defender-for-endpoint-part-1/</guid><description>Vulnerability Management is HARD nderstanding patch compliance is mission critical task for all organizations regardless of their size or affiliation. What a lot of organizations struggle with is the different between vulnerabilities and patch compliance. As a result a lot of companies end up buying expensive third party tools to scan their environment for vulnerabilities, which happens to include your base Microsoft Patches.
These vulnerability scans result in providing a huge sometimes seemingly unconquerable list for the IT department.</description></item><item><title>To Do With Siri</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/to-do-with-siri/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/to-do-with-siri/</guid><description>It’s just after the first of the year, and I’m sure those New Years resolutions are still burning in the background of everyone’s heads. What better way to accomplish those resolutions than using the tools we have available to us!
Well, I tried to use Microsoft ToDo last year. I really did. I found whenever I was sitting in front of a computer I was very dilligent in it’s usage and accomplishing things.</description></item><item><title>Mr Shiba What Time Is It - Get Time Remotely</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/mr-shiba-what-time-is-it-get-time-remotely/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/mr-shiba-what-time-is-it-get-time-remotely/</guid><description>If you’ve ever worked in a large distributed environment you’ve likely experienced time issues. Maybe it’s not even so much an issue as you just want to know where the heck in the world a machine is. Especially in the current state of the world where almost every other day I wake up and go “WHAT YEAR IS IT” every day is Monday and everything is always on fire
I’m sure you’re thinking can’t I just invoke command to it?</description></item><item><title>Find Direct Membership Collections</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/find-direct-membership-collections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/find-direct-membership-collections/</guid><description>Direct Membership rules are frequently a topic for debate due to performance, and other challenges. However, if you work in an environment where you share Configuration Manager with several other admins you might not know just how many collections you have with direct memberships, or where they are.
SQL Query SQL, something most configuration admins are uncomfortable with for some reason or another. In this particular case is probably the fastest and most direct method of acquiring the information you want.</description></item><item><title>MEMCM Community Hub Getting Started</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/memcm-community-hub-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/memcm-community-hub-getting-started/</guid><description>It’s the moment we’ve all been waiting for!
In response to this little feedback feature from one Steven Owen – now an employee at Microsoft:
https://configurationmanager.uservoice.com/forums/300492/suggestions/20509528 Microsoft has added the long awaited community hub and now it’s more than just the documentation! In fact you’ll soon be able to submit your own features to it!
We&amp;#39;re VERY close to opening the doors broadly to the Community hub. Question for all you #ConfigMgr admin&amp;#39;s: What type of safeguards and gates should we put in front of the community?</description></item><item><title>Finding OU's With Workstations - PowerShell Performance Is Weird</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/finding-ous-with-workstations-powershell-performance-is-weird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 12:17:06 -0400</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/finding-ous-with-workstations-powershell-performance-is-weird/</guid><description>I was recently asked to implement LAPS for a customer. Nothing unusual there. This particular environment was new to me which meant it was time to investigate their OU structure.
Why does OU structure matter? When implementing laps there are a few things to keep in mind. First, you need to extend the schema. Then you need to grant computers permission to access the newly created attributes… Well to accomplish this you need to assign the self permission in your root computers OU but are you sure you got them all?</description></item><item><title>Discord Tips and Tricks</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/discord-tips-and-tricks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 12:24:40 -0400</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/discord-tips-and-tricks/</guid><description>With social distancing people are looking for reliable and simple way to connect with friends and family. For many the “gaming” platform Discord has become their way to connect. Discord while incredibly easy to set up, especially compared to its former competitors Ventrillo and Teamspeak, is not always intuitive for first time users.
Now, as some of my readers know I’m an administrator over at the WinAdmins discord. A community with a focus on professional development that also acts as a gateway for IT professionals to stay in contact between conferences you can join it here but finish reading before you do.</description></item></channel></rss>