<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>PowerShell - Tag - JordanTheITGuy</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/tags/powershell/</link><description>PowerShell - Tag - JordanTheITGuy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/tags/powershell/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Find Log4J With Intune Proactive Remediations</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/find-log4j-with-intune-proactive-remediations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/find-log4j-with-intune-proactive-remediations/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/blogPosts/MakeScriptPackage.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>On December 10th 2021 CVE-2021-44228 was unveiled- queue the mass panic. A simple logging component which had been around for… forever in a whole bunch of things including but not limited to Minecraft.
Update: February 6th 2022 - It&rsquo;s worth nothing that even now three months later this vulnerability is still having massive impact all over the world as the threat hunting methods originally devised were limited in their nature. In fact, we have even seen cases where grey hat hackers were using the exploit to patch the exploit.]]></description></item><item><title>Automatic Deployment Rule Update ID Translation</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/automatic-deployment-rule-update-id-translation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/automatic-deployment-rule-update-id-translation/</guid><description>If you’ve ever worked with Automatic Deployment Rules, at some point an update has failed to download. While you might be familiar with the RuleEngine.log file, did know the “updateID” is the “CI_ID”? If you’ve ever tried to find a software update via CI_ID, you know you’re going to one of two places, and neither of them is the console. Essentially, if you’re here you’re looking for an easy way to figure out what update caused this error:</description></item><item><title>Query Defender for Endpoint Part 2</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/query-defender-for-endpoint-part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/query-defender-for-endpoint-part-2/</guid><description>Part Two on Getting Data from Defender for Endpoint This blog is the second post in a multipart series on how to get data from Defender for endpoint and analyze the patching data that is returned. Previously, we covered how to build a token, and request data from the Defender for endpoint API. This time we will cover how to create an azure app registration that allows the minimum required permissions to gather this data.</description></item><item><title>Query Defender for Endpoint Part 1</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/query-defender-for-endpoint-part-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/query-defender-for-endpoint-part-1/</guid><description>Vulnerability Management is HARD nderstanding patch compliance is mission critical task for all organizations regardless of their size or affiliation. What a lot of organizations struggle with is the different between vulnerabilities and patch compliance. As a result a lot of companies end up buying expensive third party tools to scan their environment for vulnerabilities, which happens to include your base Microsoft Patches.
These vulnerability scans result in providing a huge sometimes seemingly unconquerable list for the IT department.</description></item><item><title>PowerShell Get Members Of Group</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell_get_members_of_group/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell_get_members_of_group/</guid><description>Every now and again there comes a need to get the members of a group and manipulate that data in some fashion.
Now there are many ways to skin this cat and work with this data from VBscript, to utilizing DSquery to Quest Powershell CMDLETS to just raw powershell cmdlets.
Rather than spend time writing a new script every time you work at a different place or having to change constants in a script I spent some time writing a quick powershell script that accepts some variable information an outputs a CSV, or TXT file (your choice) with the user’s SAMaccountName combined with first and last name for all members of that group.</description></item><item><title>Powershell Change The Local Administrator Account/Password</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell_change_localadminpassword/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/powershell_change_localadminpassword/</guid><description>What Happened? Back in May of 2014 Microsoft released a windows update – MS14-025 – that removed the ability to push out passwords to workstations remotely using group policy due to issues with elevation of privilege. If that patch is applied it’s a rather large pain to change the local admin after that without something like SCCM in place.
Working Around the Issue After working through some similar issues and reading a few TechNet Articles I decided to build a quick and slightly dirty powershell script to do several things as needed.</description></item></channel></rss>