<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ConfigMgr - Tag - JordanTheITGuy</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/tags/configmgr/</link><description>ConfigMgr - Tag - JordanTheITGuy</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/tags/configmgr/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automatic Deployment Rule Update ID Translation</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/automatic-deployment-rule-update-id-translation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/automatic-deployment-rule-update-id-translation/</guid><description>&lt;div class="featured-image">
&lt;img src="/images/blogPosts/ADR-UpdateIDTranslation/UpdateGatherData.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
&lt;/div>If you’ve ever worked with Automatic Deployment Rules, at some point an update has failed to download. While you might be familiar with the RuleEngine.log file, did know the “updateID” is the “CI_ID”? If you’ve ever tried to find a software update via CI_ID, you know you’re going to one of two places, and neither of them is the console. Essentially, if you’re here you’re looking for an easy way to figure out what update caused this error:</description></item><item><title>Find Direct Membership Collections</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/find-direct-membership-collections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/find-direct-membership-collections/</guid><description>Direct Membership rules are frequently a topic for debate due to performance, and other challenges. However, if you work in an environment where you share Configuration Manager with several other admins you might not know just how many collections you have with direct memberships, or where they are.
SQL Query SQL, something most configuration admins are uncomfortable with for some reason or another. In this particular case is probably the fastest and most direct method of acquiring the information you want.</description></item><item><title>MEMCM Community Hub Getting Started</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/memcm-community-hub-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/memcm-community-hub-getting-started/</guid><description>It’s the moment we’ve all been waiting for!
In response to this little feedback feature from one Steven Owen – now an employee at Microsoft:
https://configurationmanager.uservoice.com/forums/300492/suggestions/20509528 Microsoft has added the long awaited community hub and now it’s more than just the documentation! In fact you’ll soon be able to submit your own features to it!
We&amp;#39;re VERY close to opening the doors broadly to the Community hub. Question for all you #ConfigMgr admin&amp;#39;s: What type of safeguards and gates should we put in front of the community?</description></item><item><title>ConfigMgr - 1910 User Policy for Multiple User Sessions</title><link>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/configmgr-1910-user-policy-for-multiple-user-sessions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 12:39:33 -0400</pubDate><dc:creator>Jordan Benzing</dc:creator><guid>http://preview.jordantheitguy.com/posts/configmgr-1910-user-policy-for-multiple-user-sessions/</guid><description>Making things nice for your friends Something I like to do when building a new configuration manager environment is to create and deploy an admin tool box. This is especially easy when you have tools like PatchMyPC as you can pre-package certain applications like SQL Management studio using the enterprise plus subscription features. When I do this I’m usually not the only consumer of this toolbox, and it’s usually needed on different workstations and servers by various admins in my team.</description></item></channel></rss>